Let us start our investigation on the device, how we can find out someone's connector
from through the RDP.
Let us jump on to the logs.
So, we do not want to check the system logs, we need to check the security logs.
That is for some time and let us filter out the 4, 6, 2, 4 and I already said if it is an
interactive logon, the logon type will be 2 and network logon in a previous section we
have seen in packet that will be a 3, if it is an RDP logon then the logon type will be
10.
So, if you investigate this logon type 10, the account name was user, so here you can
see the source network IP address, you got it.
So, if you see this thing logon type 10, you can find there is something someone connected
from that RDP, logon type 10, let us search for 4, 6, 2, 4, I, 10, even, I already.
And we will see remote interactive, okay, user logged into this computer remotely using
two minute service or remote desktop, you got this.
So, this is how you need to figure out someone connected from an RDP, okay.
So, that is all about this video, we are clear about RDT and we will move on to the next
video, see you guys, bye bye.